

PROFILE

Data Scientist/Software Developer with 3+ years of board-based experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Proficient in predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining, as well as scripting languages, including Python. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualification into substantial deliverables.

CONTACT

PHONE: 662-313-4033

WEBSITE:

www.dhruvinpatel.info

EMAIL

Dhruvinp895@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/dhruvin-patel88/

GITHUB:

github.com/dhruvin88

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Artificial Intelligence
Natural Language Progressing
Graph learning
Computer Vision
Web Development
Microservices
RESTful APIs
GraphQL
Tennis
Ping Pong
Video Games

DHRUVIN PATEL

Data Scientist

WORK EXPERIENCE

CoreLogic, Professional Data Scientist

Oct 2021 - Current

- Implemented custom computer vision models using Resnets, U-Nets, etc
- Built deep learning classification model to predict key property attributes
- Analyzed and assessed existing models and provided projected lift from model refreshes and new data acquisitions
- Refreshed existing marketing models for the mortgage industry improving performance

CoreLogic, Professional Software Engineer

July 2019 - Oct 2021

- Lead development of two payment project initiatives
- Refactor existing code base to new design and simpler form
- Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleagues
- Pursue agile design, development, and testing

University of Mississippi, Graduate Assistant

Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Aid in web/app development and software design courses
- Assisting students with projects and assignments
- Grading quizzes, exams, and projects for correctness

EDUCATION

University of Mississippi

M.S. in Engineering Science Aug 2017 – May 2019 Emphasis: Computer Science GPA: 4.0

University of Mississippi

B.S. in Computer Science Aug 2013 – May 2017 Minor: Business, Math

GPA: 3.80

SKILLS

Python	Pytorch	Matlab
GCP	React	MS Office
.Net Framework	SQL	Stripe API
C#	Windows	MacOS
Java	Linux	Intellj
Tensorflow	Git	VS Code
Angular	TFS	Eclipse
HTML	Jira	RabbitMQ